# Michael Nicholas

Lead Product and Technical Intern

61 Cedar Avenue, Rockville Centre, NY 11570

michaelrvc@gmail.com

(516) 459 3414

in linkedin.com/in/michael-nicholas-0620/

https://github.com/MichaelNicholas1

michaelnicholas1.github.io

# **Career Objective**

Technical and product development professional: Graduated Summa Cum Laude from the University at Albany with a degree in Computer Science and completed the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Exhibits expertise over a multitude of technical areas, including data-manipulation and visualization through spreadsheets, R/RStudio, and MySQL, UI/UX wireframing and prototyping in Figma, and front-end web development through the use of HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Strives to translate these hard skills and natural leadership and communication prowess to elevate teams to new heights through promoting data-driven decision-making and agile product management values and principles.

## **Experience**

IdeasFWD, Remote Lead Product and Technical Intern

January 2021 - PRESENT

- Effectively leads the product analysis, research, and technical division at a small start-up company by helping design and build the foundation for a mobile, creativity- focused insights gathering application akin to Sprig, called <u>WeCreatives</u>.
- Handles data analytics and visualization, application prototyping, mockups, and wireframing using Figma, weekly agile sprint structure, task delegation / management, and operates as business liaison in presenting completed deliverables
- Detail-oriented leadership supplemented with excellent communication and collaboration skills put towards application's first pitch deck development as well

Beemo, FH Münster Software Engineer Intern, Ubiquitous Computing and Human-Computer Interaction

March 2020 - April 2020

- Worked on a small, international scrum team of software engineers in Germany to learn about and develop various projects through the UAS7 internship study program via collaboration with Beemo software engineering laboratory
- Applied an adaptable mindset towards new technologies, in particular by learning Angular, towards updating the driver window for FischerTechnik, a brand of construction toys used to teach about engineering principles and simple machines

#### Advising Plus & Academic Support, University at Albany Academic Tutor for Informatics

Fall + Spring Semesters from January 2018 - December 2019

 Sole informatics tutor for both Programming for Problem Solving and Introduction to Web Technologies classes at UAlbany, that covered topics in Python, HTML, CSS, and Javascript; held walk-in office hours three hours a week while remaining on-call for one-on-one appointments to help students bolster their problem-solving skills

#### **Education**

#### Google, Data Analytics Professional Certificate

June 2021 - August 2021 - Completed an extensive job-ready Google Career training program that focused on bolstering proficiency in existing technical spaces such as data cleaning, visualization, and project management, while also learning how to interpret and transform complex data into actionable and clear insights.

University at Albany, State University of New York, Albany, NY Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, Minors in Business and Informatics

August 2016 - May 2020 - GPA: 3.820

### **Relevant Projects**

- Developed a bootstrapped personal portfolio web hosted on GitHub, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, found at <a href="https://michaelnicholas1.github.io">https://michaelnicholas1.github.io</a>
- Personal PHP project web hosted on Heroku to plot out player-character mastery data using Riot Game's developer API for their game "League of Legends", including sortable and togglable information and storing user data within a MySQL database
- Competitive, fast-paced senior group project to create a next generation asset portfolio management application titled "TradeX" with new deliverables tacked on as time progresses; with bidding to impress "consumer" at intermittent stages.

# **Awards**

- Dean's List August 2016 May 2020
- Presidential Scholarship August 2016 May 2020
- Honors College at University at Albany August 2016 May 2018